<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Task</string>
    <string name="blog_head">Makoto Shinkai Retrospective: Weathering With You</string>
    <string name="user_name">DoctorKev</string>
    <string name="anonymous">Anonymous</string>
    <string name="published">Published in AniTAY-Official</string>
    <string name="perg1">With this, I finally come to the end of my detailed retrospective on the anime film-directing career of famed creator Makoto Shinkai. The critically-acclaimed Suzume (2022) was his most recent movie, and his previous work was 2019’s Weathering With You, which assumed the unenviable job of succeeding his breakout hit your name.</string>
    <string name="perg2">I previously reviewed Weathering With You in early 2020 during its initial UK theatrical release, so I prevaricated over whether to include it in this retrospective, because I’d already covered it. However, considering how closely linked it is thematically with both its preceding and anteceding films, plus the fact that the manga adaptation and Shinkai’s own novelisation are both now available in English, it seems unwise to forgo the chance at a second appraisal, in its updated context.</string>
    <string name="perg3">To avoid retreading old ground, this won’t be a re-review of the movie. My feelings on Weathering With You haven’t changed much since my original article. I liked it a lot then, I still like it a lot now. On balance, I think your name. is the superior movie, but Weathering With You still stands head and shoulders above most other recent anime films in terms of entertainment value, thematic interest, stunning technical achievement and sheer beauty.</string>
    <string name="perg4">What mostly interests me is in the evolution of Shinkai’s themes in his three most recent films, and his gradual abandonment of his biggest obsession — ill-fated teenage love, frustrated by distance and time. With Voices of a Distant Star he set out with a short statement of intent to explore yearning and separation. The Place Promised in Our Early Days stretched this out to feature-length, and with 5cm Per Second he refined his theme at the expense of featuring infuriatingly passive characters essentially doing nothing but moping for an hour.</string>
    <string name="perg5">With Children Who Chase Lost Voices he took a detour into Ghibli-homage territory, with death as the main instigator of separation, and romance only a tiny component of the whole. Garden of Words returned to romance, but this time the separation was an age-gap power-imbalance relationship. With your name. he truly perfected his mix of teenage longing, otherworldly wonder and supernatural separation, and made the film he’d been building his whole career towards. After producing that nearly flawless masterpiece, it was unlikely he’d ever match it — but he gave it one hell of a try anyway.</string>
    <string name="perg6">Weathering With You does have a strong romantic component — but this time the central characters spend much of their time together, and only in the final third of the film are they torn apart. Rather than emulating the rage-inducing passivity of 5cm’s protagonists, Weathering With You’s Hodaka literally moves Heaven and Earth to win Hina back from her supernatural fate. The later Suzume also features similarly supernatural separation, but it barely functions as a romance, and Shinkai is on record stating that what minimal romance content is there, he was forced to include by his producers. Shinkai clearly recognises he’s done all he can with his previous obsessions, and he’s desperate to move on.</string>
    <string name="perg7">With your name., Weathering With You, and Suzume, we see Shinkai introduce and explore new themes — primarily the effect of natural disasters upon Japanese society and individuals, and to do this he integrates many aspects of traditional Japanese religious beliefs — both Buddhist and Shinto. (Contrary to popular Western assumptions, Shinto is not just a local Japanese interpretation of Buddhism — it’s a separate belief system altogether, though culturally practices from both are often melded and syncretised.) Weathering With You in particular references the primarily Buddhist Obon festival that focuses on the veneration of ancestor spirits.</string>
    <string name="bio">Physician. Obsessed with anime, manga, comic-books. Husband and father. Christian. Fascinated by tensions between modern culture and traditional faith. Bit odd.</string>
</resources>